Episode 18
에피소드 18
ma'am.
부인.
Shen...
쉔...
Mother, look at Shen.
어머니, 쉔을 보세요.
my son
내 아들.
How can that be?
어떻게 그럴 수 있니?
How could he die?
그가 어떻게 죽을 수 있었습니까?
Stop.
멈추다.
Put your hands away.
손을 치우세요.
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐하는거야?
to...
에게...
- I don't want you here. - honey.
- 난 당신이 여기 있는 걸 원하지 않아요. - 여보.
- He died because of you. - honey!
- 당신 때문에 그 사람이 죽었어요. - 여보!
He died because of you. I know that?
당신 때문에 그 사람이 죽었어요. 그거 알아?
to!
에게!
He's still worried about you...
그 사람이 아직도 널 걱정하고 있어...
Until his last breath.
그의 마지막 숨까지.
- He died because of you. - honey.
- 당신 때문에 그 사람이 죽었어요. - 여보.
- You are the culprit. - ma'am.
- 범인은 바로 당신이에요. - 부인.
- I don't want you here.
- 난 당신이 여기 있는 걸 원하지 않아요.
- Everything is your fault. - ma'am.
- 모든게 다 너의 잘못이야. - 부인.
let's go Come on, ma'am.
우리가 가자. 어서요, 부인.
You can go too.
당신도 갈 수 있습니다.
My beloved daughter...
사랑하는 내 딸...
This isn't your fault.
이것은 당신의 잘못이 아닙니다.
Your mother is overcome with grief.
당신의 어머니는 슬픔에 휩싸여 있습니다.
He didn't mean to say that.
그 사람은 그런 말을 하려고 한 게 아니었어요.
Don't take it to heart.
마음에 두지 마십시오.
Dad thought...
아빠는 생각했어요...
I am already raising a useless son.
이미 쓸모없는 아들을 키우고 있습니다.
And everything he does...
그리고 그가 하는 모든 일은...
Just harass us.
그냥 우리를 괴롭히세요.
But now he's dead...
그러나 이제 그는 죽었고...
And I have a feeling Dad won't mind cleaning up the mess...
그리고 아빠는 엉망진창을 치워도 괜찮을 것 같은 느낌이 드는데 ...
Someone made it.
누군가가 만든 것입니다.
That person is useless...
그 사람은 쓸모가 없어...
And I never want to change it.
그리고 결코 바꾸고 싶지 않습니다.
but...
하지만...
at last...
결국...
He did an impressive job.
그는 인상적인 일을 했습니다.
He makes us very proud.
그는 우리를 매우 자랑스럽게 만듭니다.
for years...
수년간...
Dad worked hard and accomplished everything.
아빠는 열심히 일했고 모든 일을 해냈어요.
To get promoted.
승진하려면.
His father plans to pave the way for him.
아버지는 그를 위해 길을 닦을 계획입니다.
Now that he's gone...
이제 그 사람은 떠났으니까...
The position of the head waiter...
헤드 웨이터의 위치...
It doesn't matter to Dad anymore.
더 이상 아빠에게는 중요하지 않습니다.
Dad said...
아빠 말은...
Would you mind thinking about what I said earlier?
내가 아까 말한 것을 생각해 보시겠어요 ?
my beloved daughter
내 사랑하는 딸.
You have done a lot for your family.
당신은 가족을 위해 많은 일을 해왔습니다 .
maybe...
아마도...
Dad was wrong.
아빠가 틀렸어요.
your sister...
당신의 자매...
You are not suited to become a trader in the first place.
애초에 트레이더가 되기에는 적합하지 않습니다 .
If dad gives up his greed...
아빠가 욕심을 버리면...
Will power and wealth grow faster?
권력 과 부가 더 빨라질 것인가...
This probably won't happen.
아마도 이런 일은 일어나지 않을 것입니다.
my beloved daughter
내 사랑하는 딸.
Now we only have you.
이제 우리에겐 당신밖에 없습니다.
You said you didn't want to live in Hwangcheong.
당신은 황청에 살고 싶지 않다고 했어요 .
Well, we won't stay here.
글쎄, 우리는 여기에 머물지 않을 것입니다.
From now on...
지금부터...
Dad will take your advice.
아빠가 네 조언을 받아들일 거야.
Dad will resign.
아빠는 사임하실 거예요.
Are you hurt?
상처받았나요?
I happened to.
내가 우연히.
Kian...
키안...
I bought this brocade satin a few days ago.
나는 며칠 전에 이 브로케이드 새틴을 샀습니다.
The color is white. Your favorite color.
색상은 흰색입니다. 당신이 가장 좋아하는 색상.
They say there is nothing like this in the world.
세상에 이것밖에 없다고 하더라고요.
I heard you're coming home today...
오늘 집에 온다고 들었는데...
So I spent a lot of money on this.
그래서 나는 이것에 많은 돈을 썼습니다.
Try on a dress made from this fabric...
이 천으로 만든 드레스를 입어보세요 ...
And Tuan will be crazy about you.
그리고 Tuan은 당신에게 열광할 것입니다.
this!
이것!
charming.
매우 좋은.
ma'am.
부인.
Does it smell familiar?
익숙한 냄새가 나나요?
no.
아니요.
Kian.
키안.
Never buy jewelry...
보석은 절대 사지 마세요...
Since marrying into the Zhong family...
종씨 가문에 결혼한 이후로....
So I bought it especially for you...
그래서 특별히 당신을 위해 샀어요...
Kian...
키안...
You are the daughter of our family.
당신은 우리 가족의 딸입니다.
You are beautiful...
아름다우세요...
And there are many people who like you.
그리고 당신을 좋아하는 사람들도 많습니다.
There is no need to suffer at Zhong Residence.
Zhong Residence에서는 고통받을 필요가 없습니다 .
I remember everything you said.
나는 당신이 말한 모든 것을 기억합니다.
Why don't you trust me?
왜 나를 믿지 않습니까?
Kian...
키안...
I have been in prison for a long time.
나는 오랫동안 감옥에 있었습니다.
Why didn't you come see me?
왜 나를 만나러 오지 않았나요?
I told you to rest...
쉬라고 했잖아...
And he said he would come later.
그리고 나중에 올 것이라고 말했습니다.
I waited all day and you didn't show up.
하루 종일 기다려도 당신은 나타나지 않았어요.
Kian...
키안...
Kian.
키안.
Is it this painful...
이정도로 괴로운지...
What if you get hit by an arrow?
화살에 맞으면?
I am your older brother.
나는 당신의 형입니다.
How could I stay still...
어떻게 가만히 있을 수 있었을까...
When you see yourself in danger?
자신이 위험에 처해 있는 것을 봤을 때?
Don't be afraid, Qian.
두려워하지 마세요, 퀴안.
I'm doing great.
잘 지내요.
I will protect you.
내가 너를 지켜줄 께.
Kian...
키안...
ma'am.
부인.
Did you see that?
그거 봤어?
See, madam?
보세요, 부인?
ma'am?
부인?
- Brother... - Madam!
- 형님... - 부인!
sisters.
자매.
ma'am.
부인.
Huaxian.
화셴.
Hua Shen is dead.
Hua Shen은 죽었습니다.
Do you know?
당신은 알고 있나요?
me too..
저도요..
I was hit by an arrow in the chest.
가슴에 화살을 맞았습니다.
Why am I safe...
나는 왜 안전한가...
And didn't he?
그리고 그는 그렇지 않았나요?
Why didn't he survive?
그는 왜 살아남지 못했습니까?
Am I dreaming?
저 꿈꾸고 있나요?
Maybe he wasn't dead.
어쩌면 그는 죽지 않았을지도 모릅니다.
I can still hear it...
아직도 들리는데...
I can still hear his voice.
나는 아직도 그의 목소리를 들을 수 있다.
I heard...
들었어...
sigh...
한숨을 쉬다...
about me.
나에 대해서.
Madam, are you okay?
부인, 괜찮으세요?
I'm not...
나는 아니에요...
I don't have any older siblings.
나는 큰 형제 자매가 없습니다.
- Madam... - This is my second time.
- 부인... - 이번이 두 번째예요.
second.
두 번째.
That's not important.
그것은 중요하지 않습니다.
I am here.
나는 여기 있다.
I will never leave.
나는 결코 떠나지 않을 것이다.
I will be by your side forever, ma'am.
저는 영원히 당신 곁에 있을 거예요 , 부인.
The Hua family's eldest son died young.
Hua 가족의 장남은 어렸을 때 죽었습니다.
What happen?
무슨 일이에요?
Look at.
바라보다.
my son
내 아들.
Shen!
쉔!
Qianzhi.
Qianzhi.
ma'am.
부인.
Why is it so noisy outside?
밖에 왜 이렇게 시끄러워?
Today is Mr. Hwa’s funeral.
오늘은 화선생의 장례식입니다.
Madam, would you please get up and get dressed ?
부인, 일어나서 옷을 입으시겠어요 ?
I don't want to go.
나는 가고 싶지 않다.
I don't want to attend the funeral.
나는 장례식에 참석하고 싶지 않습니다.
Don't wake me up.
나를 깨우지 마세요.
You must attend your brother's funeral.
당신은 동생의 장례식에 참석해야 합니다 .
It's approaching noon.
정오가 다가오고 있습니다.
If you don't go...
안 가면...
People will gossip.
사람들은 험담을 할 것입니다.
Are you crying?
울고 있나요?
How did you get here?
여기 어떻게 들어왔나요?
I was invited to attend the funeral.
나는 장례식에 참석하도록 초대받았습니다.
Who let you in?
누가 당신을 들여보냈나요?
Are all the servants dead?
하인들은 다 죽었나요?
Kian.
키안.
I am your husband...
나는 당신의 남편입니다 ...
So they won't stop me.
그래서 그들은 나를 막지 못할 것입니다.
what?
무엇?
You're being nice to me...
나한테 잘해주는구나...
Out of sympathy...
동정심에서...
Or because you feel guilty about me?
아니면 나에 대해 죄책감을 느끼기 때문에?
What kind of person do you think I am?
내가 어떤 사람이라고 생각하세요?
Kian!
키안!
- Chenz - Chen!
- 첸즈 - 첸!
I know you're upset...
당신이 화난 거 알아요...
But I have to do my hair...
하지만 머리는 해야지...
And get dressed before you leave.
그리고 떠나기 전에 옷을 입으세요.
What does that have to do with you?
그게 당신과 무슨 상관이 있나요?
I'm here to get you back.
나는 당신을 다시 데리러 왔습니다.
Take me back? Where are you going?
다시 데려다? 어디로 돌아가요?
Are you returning to your servant’s residence?
종 거주지로 돌아가시나요?
I'm watching you and Mu Yao...
당신과 Mu Yao를 지켜보고 있습니다 ...
Sharing love with each other...
서로 사랑을 나누며...
And pretend not to know...
그리고 모른 척...
While I live alone in my own home?
내가 내 집에서 혼자 사는 동안 ?
Kian.
키안.
The servants in the bell garden seem to be too busy...
종 정원의 하인들은 너무 바쁠 것 같습니다 ...
And forget it.
그리고 잊어버리세요.
Qianzhi, tell someone to urge you tomorrow.
Qianzhi, 내일 누군가에게 촉구하라고 하세요.
Why ask about the divorce papers signed by the young master...
왜 젊은 스승이 서명한 이혼 서류에 대해 물어보세요 ...
It hasn't been sent here yet.
아직 여기로 전송되지 않았습니다.
Did you go to the temple to see Young Master?
영 스승님을 만나러 종원에 가셨나요 ?
correct.
옳은.
I'm done with you now
난 너랑은 이제 끝났어
I'll have someone bring my stuff back ...
누군가 내 물건을 다시 가져오라고 할게요 ...
And my men will be at the bell residence tomorrow.
그리고 내 부하들은 내일 종 거주지에 있습니다.
Now let's break it all down...
이제 다 분해해보자 ...
Because we will never meet again.
왜냐하면 우리는 다시는 만날 수 없을 것이기 때문입니다.
Kian, are you done?
키안, 끝났어?
let me go
날 보내줘
- Let go. - Kian!
- 놔줘. - 키안!
How dare you, you rude boy!
감히, 이 무례한 소년아!
Get out!
나가세요!
Hua Rongzhou is my bodyguard.
Hua Rongzhou는 나의 경호원입니다.
You cannot command him.
당신은 그에게 명령할 수 없습니다.
Please don't disturb me.
방해하지 마십시오.
I only take orders from my mistress.
나는 여주인의 명령만 받습니다 .
Get out of here, Zhong Yeran!
여기서 나가세요, 종예란!
What are you doing, are you bothering me?
뭐하는 거야, 날 괴롭히는 거야?
You've already made your choice, so don't be swayed.
이미 선택을 했으니 흔들리지 마세요 .
Do you really want to get kicked out?
정말 쫓겨나고 싶나요?
Hua Chen.
화첸.
Because you insist that I divorce ...
당신이 나한테 이혼하라고 고집하니까 ...
Okay...
그럴게요...
do whatever you want.
원하는 대로 하세요.
Jong-ye is...
종예란...
When you return, deliver the message to Mu Yao.
돌아오면 Mu Yao에게 메시지를 전달하세요 .
He owed...
그는 빚을 졌다...
Now I have two lives.
이제 나에게는 두 개의 생명이 있습니다.
Did Zhong Yeran hit you hard?
종예란이 당신을 세게 때렸나요 ?
Are you hurt?
상처받았나요?
You don't look good.
당신은 표정이 좋지 않습니다.
I'm doing great.
잘 지내요.
If something like this happens again...
또 이런 상황이 닥치면 ..
Don't act hastily...
성급하게 행동하지 마세요 ...
And just do as I tell you.
그리고 내가 시키는 대로만 하세요.
Otherwise, instead of helping me...
그렇지 않으면 나를 돕는 대신에...
You will harass me.
당신은 나를 괴롭힐 것입니다.
I can finish it...
마무리할 수 있어...
My own problem.
내 자신의 문제.
You need to see a therapist.
치료사를 만나야합니다.
It feels really fresh now...
이제 정말 신선해졌어요...
After the commotion with Jong Ye-ran.
종예란과의 소란 이후 .
Qianzhi, please help me prepare.
Qianzhi, 준비를 도와주세요.
Okay, ma'am.
알겠습니다, 부인.
Judge Don.
돈 판사님.
Have the murderers been caught ?
살인자들은 잡혔나 요?
Assassins appear...
나타난 암살자들...
At the Mid-Autumn Festival...
중추절 잔치 에서 ...
He committed suicide after being arrested.
체포된 뒤 자살했다.
No one is safe.
아무도 안전하지 않다.
You once said...
당신은 한때 말했다 ...
The Ge family escaped...
게씨 일가가 탈출했다는 것...
It's under your control.
그것은 당신의 통제하에 있습니다.
First, the murderers stole our perfume recipe...
첫째, 살인자들은 우리의 향수 제조법을 훔쳤습니다...
During ancestral prayer meeting.
조상기도회 중.
Then a massacre occurred...
그러다 학살이 일어났는데...
At the Mid-Autumn Festival banquet.
중추절 연회 에서 .
They come and go easily .
그들은 쉽게 왔다가 ​​갑니다 .
At the Mid-Autumn Festival banquet...
그 중추절 연회 에서 ...
The butlers of the head family...
종가의 집사들...
Come together and celebrate...
함께 모여 축하해...
But it was a golden opportunity for the assassins...
하지만 암살자들에게는 절호의 기회였으니 ...
To kill us all.
우리 모두를 죽이려고.
If your mom got hurt in this incident...
이번 사건으로 엄마가 다치셨다면 ..
How will you report this to the government?
정부에 어떻게 보고할 겁니까 ?
Teacher Jongyoung.
종영선생님.
We couldn't catch all the culprits...
범인을 모두 잡지는 못했지만 ...
I discovered something strange...
뭔가 이상한 걸 발견했어요...
About this attack.
이번 공격에 대해.
more?
더?
Judge Don.
돈 판사님.
You really discovered a lot.
정말 많은 것을 발견하셨네요.
Actually, since last year...
사실 작년부터..
The Ge family has been inactive for a long time.
Ge 가족은 오랫동안 활동하지 않았습니다.
But after causing an uproar at the memorial service...
하지만 제사식에서 난리를 피운 후...
And murder...
그리고 살인...
At the Mid-Autumn Festival...
중추절 잔치 에서 ...
Their movements...
그들의 움직임...
I'm getting more and more suspicious.
점점 의심이 가네요.
After completing the ancestral rites...
제사를 마치고..
We have expanded our search.
검색을 확대했습니다.
So what I can guarantee is...
그러므로 제가 보장할 수 있는 것은...
No more than 5 people can escape...
5명 이상 탈출 불가…
And hide in the city.
그리고 도시에 숨어요.
Dozens of assassins appeared at the banquet...
연회에는 수십명의 암살자들이 등장했는데...
But you said...
하지만 당신은 말했다 ...
Can't there be more than 5 people?
5명 이상은 안되나요?
The second strange thing is...
두번째 이상한 점은..
What I want to talk about.
내가 이야기하고 싶은 것.
Assassins' clothes and weapons...
암살자들의 옷과 무기들...
It's not like before.
이전과 다릅니다.
After checking with the driver...
기사님께 확인 후..
And there is an experienced clothing store owner in the neighborhood...
그리고 동네에 경험 많은 옷가게 주인이 있는데 ...
I'm sure...
나는 확신 해...
They come from two different groups.
그들은 서로 다른 두 그룹 출신입니다.
Two different groups?
두 개의 다른 그룹?
correct.
옳은.
Those who attack the ancestral rites...
제사식을 공격하는 자들 ...
Comes from the Ge family.
Ge 가족 출신입니다.
Meanwhile, the other groups...
그 사이 다른 그룹은...
Maybe there aren't enough people...
사람이 부족할 수도 있고...
So they could only hire temporary help.
그래서 그들은 일시적인 도움만을 고용할 수 있었습니다.
Besides, they are in a hurry.
게다가 그들은 서두르고 있습니다.
That's why there's a big difference.
그렇기 때문에 큰 차이가 있습니다.
As I said earlier...
앞서 말했듯이...
Someone inside helps them.
내부의 누군가가 그들을 도와줍니다.
remember...
기억해...
When Teacher Wu came to town...
우 선생이 마을에 왔을 때...
He tried several times...
그는 여러 번 시도했습니다 ...
Asking Mrs. Jong on a date...
종 부인에게 데이트신청...
And that's very strange.
그리고 그것은 매우 이상합니다.
You suspect...
당신은 의심합니다 ...
Is it my senior or the Hua Family?
나의 선배인가, 아니면 Hua Family인가?
I'm just expressing my doubts.
나는 단지 의심을 표명하고 있습니다.
No wonder you can't find anything .
아무것도 찾을 수 없는 것도 당연합니다 .
You're targeting the wrong people!
잘못된 사람을 타겟팅하고 있습니다!
Murder at the banquet...
연회에서의 살인..
It must have been planned in advance.
사전에 계획되었음이 틀림없습니다.
They won't look for extra people at the last minute.
그들은 마지막 순간에 추가 인원을 찾지 않을 것입니다 .
If the two groups cooperate as you said...
말씀하신대로 두 그룹이 협력한다면 ...
At least they will...
적어도 그들은 그럴 것이다...
Match your clothes and weapons.
옷과 무기를 일치시킵니다 .
How could they make such a big mistake...
어떻게 그 사람들이 그렇게 큰 실수를 할 수 있었는지...
So can you find it?
그럼 찾을 수 있나요?
Please give me a moment, Master Jongyoung.
잠시만 시간을 주십시오, 종영스승님.
We will work hard to find the culprit.
범인을 찾기 위해 열심히 노력하겠습니다 .
I still don't know...
아직도 잘 모르겠어...
Are there two groups of assassins at the banquet?
연회에 암살자들이 두 집단이 있는 걸까요 ...
So please keep this a secret.
그러니 이 일은 비밀로 해주세요.
I don't want to warn the enemy.
나는 적에게 경고하고 싶지 않습니다 .
composure. My lips are locked.
침착. 내 입술이 잠겨 있습니다.
Would you like to go, madam?
가실래요, 부인?
You need to take a bodyguard with you.
경호원을 데리고 가야 합니다.
not needed. I don't want anyone to know.
필요 없음. 나는 누구에게도 알리고 싶지 않습니다.
Can I come with you, ma'am?
같이 가도 될까요, 부인?
of course.
물론.
Young Master.
젊은 스승님.
Someone there sent another message.
거기 누군가가 또 다른 메시지를 보냈어요.
Come closer.
가까이 오세요.
Young Master.
젊은 스승님.
There are too many people watching Judge Wang...
왕판사를 보는 사람이 너무 많다 ...
And they are watching his every move closely.
그리고 그들은 그의 일거수일투족을 예의주시하고 있습니다.
In the end, my eyes were focused on him...
결국 그에게 시선이 쏠렸는데...
You can investigate secretly.
비밀리에 조사할 수 있습니다.
Do you know the number of bodyguards...
경호원 숫자를 아시나요...
Of all the households in town.
마을의 모든 가구 중.
to find out...
알아내다...
Where do these murderers come from?
이 살인자들은 어디서 왔는가?
Okay, Young Master.
좋습니다, 영 마스터님.
Makam Huashen
마캄 후아셴
What is that?
그것은 무엇입니까?
It's pretty scary here at night.
이곳은 밤에 꽤 무섭습니다.
What if we were next to your wife ?
우리가 부인 옆에 있으면 어떨까요 ?
This is Young Master Hua.
바로 Hua Young Master입니다.
There is nothing scary.
무서운 것은 없습니다.
sisters.
자매.
It's late again.
또 늦었어.
I don't want to take you to the grave with everyone else...
나는 당신을 다른 사람들과 함께 무덤으로 데려가고 싶지 않습니다 ...
So I came alone.
그래서 저는 혼자 왔습니다.
He said we would talk after the banquet.
연회 후에 얘기하자고 했어요 .
This time I kept my promise.
이번에는 약속을 지켰습니다.
You wouldn't blame me , would you?
당신은 나를 비난하지 않을 것입니다 , 그렇죠?
This delicious wine...
이 맛있는 와인...
It is going through a long maturation process .
오랜 숙성 과정을 거치고 있습니다 .
Please be nice to my sister
내 여동생에게 잘 대해주세요
Here's a toast to you.
여기 당신에게 건배합니다.
Your brother is taking care of you.
당신의 동생이 당신을 돌보고 있습니다.
I'll be back, brother.
난 돌아올게요, 형제님.
Let's meet again next time.
다음에 또 만나요.
How long has Muda been standing here ?
무다는 여기에 얼마나 오랫동안 서 있었나요?
It's only been 30 minutes.
이제 겨우 30분밖에 안 됐어요.
How do you know I'm here?
내가 여기 있다는 걸 어떻게 아나요?
I know your heart is soft.
나는 당신의 마음이 부드럽다는 것을 압니다.
You never stay still...
넌 절대 가만히 있지 않아...
When Hua Shen was in trouble.
Hua Shen이 곤경에 처했을 때.
Others think you didn't attend the funeral...
다른 사람들은 당신이 장례식에 참석하지 않았다고 생각하는데 ...
Because it's heartless.
무정하기 때문이죠.
But I am sure...
그러나 나는 확신합니다 ...
You are coming.
당신은 오고 있다.
Why are you here?
당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
I have something prepared for you.
널 위해 준비 한게있어.
Surat Perserian
수라트 페르세라이안
Just ask the servant to bring it to you .
하인 에게 가져오라고 하시면 됩니다 .
You do not need to come in person.
직접 오실 필요는 없습니다.
i miss you.
보고 싶어요.
This is inappropriate, Young Master.
이건 부적절해요, 영 마스터님.
late. I'd better go back.
늦었 어. 나는 돌아가는 것이 좋겠다.
Are there any traces of the culprit?
범인의 흔적은 없는지...
At the banquet that day?
그날 연회에서요?
Not yet.
아직 아님.
They erased all traces.
그들은 모든 흔적을 지웠습니다.
The caught murderers chose to take their own lives...
붙잡힌 살인범들은 스스로 목숨을 끊는 것을 선택했는데…
By poisoning yourself.
자신을 중독시킴으로써.
No one is safe.
아무도 안전하지 않다.
They also left no traces at the crime scene.
그들은 또한 범죄 현장에 어떤 흔적도 남기지 않았습니다.
Besides, it's always difficult...
게다가 항상 힘든데..
Looking for the Ge family.
Ge 가족을 찾고 있습니다.
Military law was once again imposed on the city.
군법이 다시 한번 도시에 부과되었습니다.
Has the culprit been caught?
범인이 잡혔나...
Are they wearing the same clothes and carrying the same weapons?
같은 옷을 입고 같은 무기를 들고 있나요?
Why are you asking this?
왜 이런 걸 묻는 거죠?
It seems less harmonious.
덜 조화로운 것 같습니다.
Even among themselves there are disputes.
심지어 그들 사이에도 분쟁이 일어나고 있습니다 .
It's as if their goals are different.
마치 그들의 목표가 다른 것 같습니다.
The ability to remain calm in any situation...
어떤 상황에서도 침착함을 유지하는 능력 ...
surprising.
놀랍다.
You don't have to say anything if you don't want to.
원하지 않으면 말하지 않아도 됩니다 .
Don't ignore me by saying things like that.
그런 말로 나를 무시하지 마세요 .
Kian.
키안.
Even if it's just the two of us...
우리 둘만 있어도...
This is inappropriate behavior.
이는 부적절한 행동입니다.
What do you think about me?
나를 어떻게 생각하세요?
Don't you always know how I feel?
내 기분이 어떤지 넌 항상 모르지?
But now you've given me the rules.
그러나 이제 당신은 나에게 규칙을 알려주었습니다.
Young Master, when did you change your goals?
영 마스터님 , 언제 목표를 바꾸셨나요 ?
Nothing has changed.
아무것도 변하지 않았다.
Always you.
항상 당신.
What about Muyao?
무야오는 어떻습니까?
Why do you keep linking me with that person?
왜 자꾸 그 사람이랑 나를 연결하는 거야?
You said...
당신은 말했다 ...
The way we look at that person is different...
그 사람을 바라보는 시선도 다르고...
Compared to the way you see me.
당신이 나를 보는 방식과 비교하면.
Of course it's different.
물론 다릅니다.
I see you differently...
나는 당신을 다르게 본다 ...
Because I like you.
난 당신을 좋아하기 때문에.
That never changes.
그것은 결코 변하지 않습니다.
Behind the rock garden earlier...
아까 바위정원 뒤편에...
You mentioned Mu Yao. What does it mean?
Mu Yao를 언급하셨습니다. 무슨 뜻이에요?
Mu Yao is a special woman...
Mu Yao는 특별한 여자입니다 ...
Wu Shuomo also liked it.
Wu Shuomo도 그것을 좋아했습니다.
Young Master, this is a reminder for you.
젊은 스승님, 당신을 위한 알림입니다.
How do I know?
어떻게 알 수 있나요?
A man cannot hide his affection for his lover.
남자는 연인에 대한 애정을 숨길 수 없습니다 .
The way you look at Mu Yao and me...
당신이 Mu Yao와 나를 보는 방식...
Very different.
매우 다릅니다.
Women are sensitive to such things.
여자들은 그런 것에 민감해요 .
Of course, the way I look at Mu Yao is...
물론 내가 무야오를 바라보는 시선은...
It's not the way I see you.
내가 당신을 보는 방식과 다릅니다.
I still remember the married woman...
아직도 생각나는 유부녀 ...
Also you.
또한 당신.
He is married.
그는 결혼했습니다.
Are you still thinking about it?
아직도 그것에 대해 생각하고 있나요?
of.
의.
She is a lucky woman.
그녀는 운이 좋은 여자입니다.
And the person I want to make clothes for ...
그리고 내가 옷을 만들어주고 싶은 사람 ...
The same goes for you.
당신도 마찬가지입니다.
It's done.
끝났습니다.
I want to make clothes for her .
나는 그녀를 위해 옷을 만들고 싶다 .
You and that person have the same build.
당신과 그 사람은 같은 체격을 가지고 있습니다.
Because you are here...
당신이 여기 있으니까...
Can you help me with the size?
사이즈를 도와주실 수 있나요 ?
The only thing I like is you...
내가 좋아하는 건 너뿐이야...
until now.
지금까지.
Kian.
키안.
I... I'm Mr. I married Mr.
나... 나는 Mr. Mr과 결혼했어요.
I knew it would be burdensome...
부담스러울 줄 알고...
Because of your condition...
너의 상태 때문에...
So, I didn't tell you...
그래서, 내가 너한테 말하지 않았어...
Until divorce.
이혼할 때까지.
You once used Mu Yao as an excuse...
당신은 한때 Mu Yao를 핑계로 삼았습니다 ...
To reject me.
나를 거부하기 위해.
But why does the expression...
그런데 왜 표정이...
Do you feel like you don't know anything now?
지금은 아무것도 모르는 것 같나요?
Because I understood what I meant last time...
저번에 내가 무슨 뜻인지 이해 했으니까 ...
Why are you here today?
오늘 여기에 왜 왔나요?
You are back to your normal self...
당신은 원래 모습으로 돌아왔습니다...
Fah's daughter...
화씨네 딸...
And there are no more obstacles...
그리고 더 이상 장애물이 없습니다 ...
So I came here to ask.
그래서 물어보려고 왔습니다.
Young Master, are you kidding?
영 스승님이 농담하시나요?
Think about our identity.
우리의 정체성을 생각해 보세요.
We are not suitable for each other even now.
우리는 지금도 서로에게 적합하지 않습니다 .
Maybe it's not appropriate...
어쩌면 적절하지 않을 수도 있습니다 ...
Let's talk about it here and now .
지금 여기서 얘기해보자 .
But I want to know how you feel
하지만 당신의 기분이 어떤지 알고 싶습니다
If you have any affection for me...
나에게 조금이라도 애정이 있다면 ...
Leave the other work to me.
다른 일은 나에게 맡겨라.
Then I will make sure you accompany me properly.
그럼 제대로 동행하게 해줄게 .
Have you seen the young master?
젊은 스승님은 못 보셨나요?
What do you see?
무엇이 보이나요?
Kian.
키안.
Leave it to me.
내게 맡겨 줘.
Expropriate...
수용하다...
And I am here for you.
그리고 나는 당신을 위해 여기 있습니다.
Can I hold your hand?
손을 잡아도 될까요?
Adigan Bonus
애디건 보너스
Please refine the ink for me.
나를 위해 잉크를 정제해 주세요.
Surat Perserian
수라트 페르세라이안
This is what he wants.
이것이 그가 원하는 것입니다.
Let Lin Jiang watch over them.
Lin Jiang이 그들을 감시하게 하세요.
Okay, Young Master.
좋습니다, 영 마스터님.
Young Master, Teacher Meng is outside.
젊은 스승님, 멩 선생님이 밖에 계십니다.
Tell him to come in.
그에게 들어오라고 말하세요.
Hello, Young Master.
안녕하세요, 영마스터님.
What is that?
그것은 무엇입니까?
His Majesty asked me to deliver some food.
폐하께서는 나에게 음식을 배달해 달라고 부탁하셨습니다.
OK. Just put it down.
괜찮은. 그냥 내려 놓으십시오.
I'm busy.
저는 바쁩니다.
If you have nothing else, you can go.
다른 것이 없다면 가셔도 됩니다.
Okay, Young Master.
좋습니다, 영 마스터님.
Excuse me.
실례하겠습니다.